这是二零二三年长沙市
初中学业水平考试英语听力部分。
现在是听力试听时间。
Have you ever heard of Boxing Day?
The celebration happens in the United Kingdom and the countries that were once part
of the British Empire.
Boxing Day falls on the day after Christmas.
The official holiday dates back to 1871,
yet no one is exactly sure how it started.
Some people think it has something to do with Christmas gifts.
In Britain, on the 26th of December,
the day after Christmas, the very rich people in Victorian times gave gifts to their
servants in small boxes.
That's why it was called Boxing Day.
Another possibility is that the name refers to money that was given to people in
need. Traditionally, a box was placed in churches to collect money.
The money from the box was given out to the poor on the day after Christmas.
No matter what Boxing Day's origins are, it's still a widely celebrated holiday.
For some, it is a big shopping day, and for others, it is a great day to eat, relax,
and watch sports.
Have you ever heard of Boxing Day?
The celebration happens in the United Kingdom and the countries that were once part
of the British Empire.
Boxing Day falls on the day after Christmas.
The official holiday dates back to 1871,
yet no one is exactly sure how it started.
Some people think it has something to do with Christmas gifts.
In Britain, on the 26th of December,
the day after Christmas, the very rich people in Victorian times gave gifts to their
servants in small boxes.
That's why it was called Boxing Day.
Another possibility is that the name refers to money that was given to people in
need. Traditionally, a box was placed in churches to collect money.
The money from the box was given out to the poor on the day after Christmas.
No matter what Boxing Day's origins are, it's still a widely celebrated holiday.
For some, it is a big shopping day, and for others, it is a great day to eat, relax,
and watch sports.
试听到此结束。
二零二三年长沙市初中学业水平考试
英语试卷第一部分听力测试
正式开始。
本部分分为第一、第二两节。
做题时，请先将答案标在试题卷上。
本部分录音内容全部结束后，再将答案转涂到答题卡上。
听力材料。
以中速朗读两遍。
speed. three A, B, and
第一节，听下面五段对话，每段对话后有一个小题，从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳。
选项：听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来回答有关小题和阅读下一
小题。
每段对话读两遍。
sentences. 2. Sam, how's the weather down there in Shanghai?
一。
It's cloudy. 3.
Tina, what do you want to be when you grow up?
I think I want to be a pilot.
4. My phone doesn't seem to be working.
Feel free to use mine if you want.
5. Mary, where are you going?
To the swimming pool.
I have swimming classes twice a week.
Mary, where are you going?
To the swimming pool.
I have swimming classes twice a
第二节，听下面六段对话或独白，每段。
对话或独白后有几个小题，从题中所给的
A, B, and and Excuse me, could you please tell me where the post office is?
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅读各个小题，
每小题。
五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听第六段材料，回答第六、七题。
Sure. Go along New Street.
Turn right at the third crossing and the post office is on your left, between the
bank and the supermarket.
Oh, it sounds a little bit far.
Yeah, you'd better take a taxi.
That's a good idea.
Thanks. me, could you please tell me where the post office is?
Sure. Go along New Street.
Turn right at the third crossing and the post office is on your left, between the
bank and the supermarket.
Oh, it sounds a little bit far.
Yeah, you'd better take a taxi.
That's a good idea.
Thanks. and ninth questions.
听第七段材料，回答第八。
Sally, look at the menu.
What would you like to eat?
I'm not sure yet.
Is there anything you especially like?
Yes, I like all kinds of fish and vegetables.
Okay. Is there any food you don't eat?
Well, I don't eat chicken, and I don't like eggs either.
Sally, look at the menu.
What would you like to eat?
I'm not sure yet.
Is there anything you especially like?
Yes, I like all kinds of fish and vegetables.
Okay. Is there any food you don't eat?
Well, I don't eat chicken, and I don't like eggs either.
听第八段材料，回答第十。
and eleventh questions.
You don't look well.
What's the matter, Emily?
I have a bad headache.
Why not see a doctor?
Yeah, I think I should.
But it's Wednesday today, and I'm supposed to in the report tomorrow.
Well, why don't you ask Miss Smith if you can hand it in later?
After all, she needs it for the meeting next Monday.
Maybe I should try.
If you need any help, just let me know.
don't look well.
What's the matter, Emily?
I have a bad headache.
Why not see a Yeah, I think I should.
But it's Wednesday today, and I'm supposed to hand in the report tomorrow.
Well, why don't you ask Miss Smith if you can hand it in later?
After all, she needs it for the meeting next Monday.
Maybe I should try.
If you need any help, just let me know.
听第九段。
材料回答第十二至十四题。
Kevin, busy doing anything?
Oh, Helen, I'm preparing a speech for tomorrow's class.
It's about a girl named Tracy Woods.
What's special about her?
She brought some dogs to help children in special education schools.
She believes that dogs can help them better their lives.
But putting dogs into a school?
I'm afraid they may mess up the schools.
Don't worry. All the dogs are specially trained.
There are now forty dogs working with children aged from six to eighteen.
Wow, what an interesting story.
I hope my classmates will love the story too.
Kevin, busy doing anything?
Oh, Helen, I'm preparing a speech for tomorrow's class.
It's about a girl named Tracy Woods.
What's special about her?
She brought some dogs to help children in special education schools.
She believes that dogs can help them better their lives.
But putting dogs into a school?
I'm afraid they may mess up the schools.
Don't worry. All the dogs are specially trained.
There are now forty dogs working with children aged from six to eighteen.
Wow, what an interesting story.
Yeah, I hope my classmates will love the story too.
听第十段材料，回答第十五至十七题。
What's help schools.
lives. Hello, I'm Jane from Sunny School.
Nice to meet you.
Do you learn music here?
Yes, I'm Peter from Greenery School.
I'm learning the piano.
Great. I'm learning the violin here.
Can you play it?
No, I think it is difficult for me.
Well, it's not that hard.
Do you play anything else?
I'm planning to learn the guitar.
Me too. By the way, some pop stars will have a concert in the park this Saturday.
Would you like to go with me?
I'd love to.
When will it start?
At 2 p.m.
Okay, see you then.
Hello, I'm Jane from Sunny School.
Nice to meet you.
Do you learn music here?
Yes, I'm Peter from Greenery School.
I'm learning the piano.
Great. I'm learning the violin here.
Can you play it?
No, I think it is difficult for me.
Well, it's not that hard.
Do you play anything else?
I'm planning to learn the guitar.
Me too. By the way, some pop stars will have a concert in the park this Saturday.
Would you like to go with me?
I'd love to.
When will it start?
At 2 p.m.
Okay, see you then.
听第十一段材料，回答第十八至。
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome aboard our city tour bus.
Let me tell you something about the tour.
First, we are going to travel through the most historic parts of the city like the
Bright Theatre for about an hour.
You will have lots of chances to take photos or just enjoy the wonderful buildings.
At 11, we'll set out for the Friendship Market.
You may buy some food and drinks from the marketplace and have a light meal in the
wood park nearby.
Then, we'll drop you off at the museum.
You'll have two hours there.
But please, please, please come back on time at 3.30 p.m.
We can't wait for any latecomers.
Now, I'll give you some instructions on safety.
Ladies and gentlemen, welcome aboard our city tour bus.
Let me tell you something about the tour.
First, we are going to travel through the most historic parts of the city like the
Bright Theatre for about an hour.
You will have lots of chances to take photos or just enjoy the wonderful buildings.
At 11, we'll set out for the Friendship Market.
You may buy some food and drinks from the marketplace and have a light meal in the
wood park nearby.
Then, we'll drop you off at the museum.
You'll have two hours there.
But please, please, come back on time at 3.30 p.m.
We can't wait for any latecomers.
Now, I'll give you some instructions on safety.
Please, please.m.
听力测试到此结束，请将试题卷上的答案转涂到答题卡上。